A Finding Aid to the Chaim Gross Papers, 1920-2004, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1926-1997; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 8.75 Linear feet Boxes 1-9, 22
  Gross's work for the Works Progress Administration is documented through correspondence, contracts, payment vouchers, and related documentation. The Federal Art Project correspondence includes a copy of Gross's Government Services Administration transcript of employment up to September 1940 and letters relating to Gross's winning entry for the competition to execute artwork for the Post Office in Irwin, Pennsylvania. The Treasury Relief Art Project files document Gross's commissions for the Post Office Department building and the Apex Building in Washington, D. C. The files include scattered personal letters from Ed Rowan and Forbes Watson. The New York World's Fair (1939) folder contains a contract for Gross's work for the France Overseas and Finnish Buildings, and related correspondence and financial records. Also documented are Gross's participation in juries for national competitions and his work as a consultant for the selection of sculptors to execute work on federal buildings.
  Correspondence with museums and galleries provides documentation of commissions and sales of Gross's artwork, many solo and group exhibitions in which he was represented, and multiple loans and gifts to various museums. These include Gross's 1977 retrospective at the Jewish Museum, exhibitions at the Smithsonian's American Art Museum, the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, and the Whitney Museum of American Art. Correspondence with Bella Fishko and Forum Gallery documents Forum Gallery's representation of Gross's artwork from 1961 through the early 1980s and indicates the lucrative nature of Gross's exhibitions during that period. Letters include account statements, appraisals, records of sales and gifts of Gross's work, and copies of correspondence relating to loans of work for exhibitions at other galleries and museums.
  Correspondence with Warren Robbins documents Robbins's efforts to engage the involvement of artists in establishing the Museum of African Art. Purchases of Gross's work in the early 1940s by museums as prominent as the Metropolitan Museum of Art and the Museum of Modern Art, are also documented here, as are Gross's gifts and loans to both museums, his involvement with the Museum of Modern Art's education committee, and his loans from his personal collection to the National Gallery of Art's first exhibition of African art in 1970.
  References to many commissions and projects appear throughout the series, including Gross's six bronze panels entitled Six Days of Creation for Temple Sharray Tefila in New York City, and his Ten Commandments for the sanctuary of the International Synagogue at John F. Kennedy Airport, New York. Correspondence with Harold and Kitty Ruttenberg relates to commissions for Temple Sinai in Pittsburgh and others and is notable also in that it includes relatively frequent replies from Renee and Chaim Gross which provide details about events in their lives and Gross's career. Correspondence with the United Nations documents Gross's commissions for watercolors and serigraph prints reproduced in three first day covers and stamps issued for the United Nations.
  Correspondence also documents Gross's work as an educator with the Educational Alliance, and with the New School for Social Research where Gross acted in various capacities, including as a teacher, donor, and jury member, and worked to support the school's plan to establish an expanded art center program with residential facilities to serve as a resource for the whole of New York City.
  Gross's involvement in many societies and associations is also documented, including his donations to, and service on the board of trustees of the Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown and the Provincetown Art Association; his election to associate and academician of the National Academy of Design; and his membership in the National Institute of Arts and Letters. Correspondence with the Sculptor's Guild Inc., and with Fimi Samour, documents the guild's activities during the 1950s-early 1980s, including exhibitions, memberships, and financial status. Sculptors Guild correspondence includes letters from artist Renata Schwebel.
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically. Individuals and organizations represented in five or more items are arranged in named files; others are arranged alphabetically in general files for each letter. Files for correspondents with no given surname, or whose names are illegible or unidentified, are arranged toward the end of the series, followed by condolence letters written to Renee Gross on the death of Chaim Gross.
  - A La Reine Margot (Margot and Rebecca), circa 1960-circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1941-1943; 1959; 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Adelphi University, 1977-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - African-American Institute, 1972-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alva Museum Replicas, Inc., 1958-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - America-Israel Cultural Foundation, Inc., 1959-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - America-Israel Cultural Foundation, Inc., 1967-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1963-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Committee for Shaare Zedek Hospital, 1978-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Federation of Arts/Magazine of Art, 1935-circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University, 1959-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University, 1971-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - American Friends of the Israel Museum, 1973-1977; 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - American-Israel World's Fair Corporation, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1957-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1961-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Mizrachi Women, 1977-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Society for Technion, Women's Division, circa 1956-circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Angel, Rivka, circa 1967-circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Anna L. Werbe Galleries, 1960-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Anti-Defamation League Appeal Women's Division, 1971-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Architectural League of New York, 1937-1948; 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Art In Federal Buildings, Forbes Watson, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1941-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Art Students' League of New York, 1926; circa 1940-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Art Vivant, Inc., 1973-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Artists Equity Association, Inc., 1947-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Artists Welfare Fund, Inc., circa 1973-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Arts Universal Research Associates, Inc., 1979-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Associated American Artists, 1941-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Association for the Help of Retarded Children, 1962-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Association for Welfare of Soldiers in Israel, circa 1970-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Atkin, Edith and Sam, circa 1960s-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Audubon Artists, Inc., 1944-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Authenticated Graphic Editions Internationale, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Avnet, Lester, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - A, General: Aa-Al, 1948-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - A, General: Ama-American I, 1936-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - A, General: American J-Ams, 1936-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - A, General: An-Aro, 1935-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - A, General: Art-Aru, 1934-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - A, General: As-Av, 1945-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1945-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Barn Gallery Associates, Inc., 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Barnes Foundation, 1959-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Barnhard, Esther and Sherwood, circa 1976-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Bass Museum of Art, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Bean, Marshall E., 1966-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Beckman, Bernie, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Begner, Edith and Jacob (Jack), circa 1962-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Beier, Norman S., 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Benay, Florence and Marcus/Woodmere Academy, 1968-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Benk, Lane, 1976-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Benrus Watch Company, Inc., 1964-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Berman, Allan and Jean R., circa 1973-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Berman, Muriel M and Philip I., 1972-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Berney, Joseph H. and Phyllis, circa 1979-circa 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Bernstein, Alice and Bo, circa 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bernstein, Alice and Bo, 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Documents Bernstein's patronage of Gross's work, including his $50,000 gift to the University of Rhode Island which was used to purchase Gross's Performers in 1972.
  - Bernstein, Irwin L. (Tiny), circa 1958-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Biddle, George, 1947-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bikel, Theodore, circa 1961-circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Birch, John and Dorothy, 1930s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Birmingham Museum of Art, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bishop, Isabel, circa 1950s-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Blume, Peter, 1940; 1963; 1974-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes a signed copy of Blume's remarks on the presentation of the American Academy of Arts and Letters award of merit medal to Gross in 1963.
  - B'Nai B'rith, circa 1961-1966; 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Boston University, 1977-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Boyer Galleries, Inc., 1934-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brandeis University, circa 1950s-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Brandywine River Museum of the Brandywine Conservancy, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brenner, Joseph and Ronnie, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Broido, Phoebe, circa 1973-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Brooklyn Association for Mental Health, Inc., 1961-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Brooklyn Museum, circa 1930-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Brown University, 1969-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Browne, Blanche and Milton, circa 1974-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Brownstone, Ethel and Lucien, circa 1964-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Burson-Marstellar Associates, Inc., 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Butler Institute of American Art, 1957-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - B, General: Ba, 1948-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - B, General: Bea-Ben, 1932-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - B, General: Ber-Bez, 1959-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - B, General: Bg-Bl, 1951-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - B, General: Bn-Bo, circa 1940-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - B, General: Bra-Brot, 1945-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - B, General: Brou-By, 1949-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Campbell, Jane and Kenneth F., circa 1967-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1938-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Castellon, Fred, circa 1959-circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Central Synagogue, 1967-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Chrysler Art Museum of Provincetown, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Cincinnati Art Museum, 1938, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - City Art Museum of St. Louis, 1946, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - City of New York, 1931-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Various departments including Board of Education and Office of the Mayor.
  - City University of New York, 1972-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Clark University, 1965-1966; 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Clayton, Sandy and Stewart, 1977-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Cohen, Howard, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Cohen, Stephanie Diamond, circa 1959-circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Colby College Art Museum, circa 1959-circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - College Art Association, 1933-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Columbia University, 1951-1982; 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Conference of Presidents of Major American Jewish Organization, 1973-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Congregation Addath Jeshurun, 1966-1969; 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Congregation Beth Achim on Gramcery Park, Brotherhood Synagogue, 1975-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Congregation Beth El, Detroit, MI (Robert N. Canvasser), 1971-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Congregation Beth El, South Orange, NJ, 1963-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Congregation B'Nai Jeshuran, 1965-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Congregation Emanu-El, San Francisco, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Congregation Gates of Heaven (Michael M. Szenes), 1966; 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE)/Artists for CORE, 1963-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Consulate General of Israel in New York, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Contemporary American Sculptors Inc., 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1951-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Cornell University (Andrew Dickson White Museum of Art/Cornell Art Tour), 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Crane, Winthrop, 1935-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Cummings, Nathan, 1977-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Cummington School (Playhouse-in-the-Hills), 1934-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Cutler, Lois/Medici II Gallery, 1970-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - C, General: C.-Ce, 1942-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - C, General: Ch-Ci, 1939-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - C, General: Cl-Com, 1936-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - C, General: Con-Cu, 1936-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Deborah Hospital, 1965-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Denholtz, Elaine G., 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Diamond, David L., 1967-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Diskin Orphan Home of Israel, 1979-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Dubiner, Samuel, 1955-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Dworsky, Florence, circa 1972-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - D, General: Da-D.C., 1944-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - D, General: De, 1936-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - D, General: Dh-Dy, 1932-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - E. P. Dutton & Company, Inc., 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Educational Alliance, 1931-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Educational Alliance, 1971-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt Memorial Foundation, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Elisofon, Eliot and Elin, circa 1942-circa 1948; 1972-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Encyclopedia Judaica, 1946-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ernst, Philip A., circa 1942-circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Eva Lee Gallery, circa 1962-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Everett, Elsie and Jack, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Everhart Museum, 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Everson Museum of Art, 1962-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ezra Academy, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - E, General: E. El, 1934-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Includes two cards from Ralph and Fanny Ellison
  - E, General: Em-Ez, 1940-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Includes 3 letters from sculptor and foundry owner in Rome, Herzl Emanuel; 2 letters from sculptor Jacob Epstein, one regarding a sculpture Epstein purchased from Gross; and a letter and a postcard from Philip Evergood.
  - Fabri, Ralph (Today's Art), 1966-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fairleigh Dickinson University, 1967-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Farber, Antje and Leonard L., circa 1974-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Federal Art Project, 1939-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Federal Art Project, 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York, 1969-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, 1966-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Feldberg, Stanley and Teddy, circa 1972-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Ferdman, Guta and Joe, circa 1948-circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Fields, Edward and Eleanor, 1976-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Documents sales of tapestries with reproductions of Gross's artwork.
  - Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, Inc., 1968-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Five Towns Music and Art Foundation, Inc., 1950; 1966-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Floch, Joseph and Mimi, circa 1960s; 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Fogelson, David and Trudye, 1976-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Forum Gallery/Bella Fishko, circa 1960-circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Forum Gallery/Bella Fishko, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Forum Gallery/Bella Fishko, 1970-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Forum Gallery/Bella Fishko, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Forum Gallery/Bella Fishko, 1979-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Franklin and Marshall College, circa 1969-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Franklin, Harry A., circa 1944-1965; 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Freund, Chaya, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Friendly, Dorothy and Fred, circa 1960-circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - F, General: F-Fei, 1940-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - F, General: Fel-Fi, 1931-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - F, General: Fl-Fo, 1945-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
    Includes a January 1945 receipt from Juliana Force for a bronze figure purchased for $500; and three greeting cards from Karl and Lillian Fortess with reproductions of original artwork.
  - F, General: Fra-Fre, 1937-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - G, General: Fri-Fu, 1939-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Galerie Cote (Victor Rosado), 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Ganeles, Benjamin and Ruth, circa 1961-circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Ganeles, David P. and Lynn (Hadassah, Ossining-Briarcliff Chapter), circa 1965-circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Garelick's Gallery (Robert Garelick), 1955-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - George Heller Memorial Foundation, Inc., 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Geva, Shlomo and Zipy, circa 1975-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Gildenhorn, Alma and Joseph B., 1972-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Glass Gallery (Wendy Glass), 1968-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Goldblatt, Noel, circa 1979-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Goldman, Tillie (American Friends of the Israel Museum Women's Division), circa 1973-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Goldsheider, Sidney, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Golenbock and Barell (Seyour Kleinman, Karen Horney Clinic), 1977-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Goodrich, Edith and Lloyd, circa 1959-circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Gordon, Ruth (later Herskovitz), circa 1960s-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Govenar, Sidney A., 1971-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Graham, Laurie and Richard, 1965-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Grooms, Mimi, Red and Family, circa 1961-circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 63)
    Includes eight letters and two envelopes illustrated by Mimi Grooms, one is oversized and housed in Box 22, Folder 1.
  - Gross, Gershon and Family, circa 1965-circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Gross, Jerome and Marjorie, circa 1975-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Gross, Renee to Chaim Gross, circa 1970-circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Grossman, Emery, 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Gutterman, Leslie Yale and Julie, 1978-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Guttman, Albee and Jerome B., 1970-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - G, General: G.-Geo, 1941-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - G, General: Ger-Gl, 1940-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 71)
    Includes three letters, one illustrated, from Eugenie Gershoy in which she expresses her admiration for Gross and references bronzes Gross bought from her; three letters from African art historian J. Werner Gillon; and two postcards from Allan Ginsberg, who delivered a tribute to Gross in 1994 at the American Academy of Arts and Letters.
  - G, General: God-Gol, 1936-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - G, General: Goo-Gou, 1939-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - G, General: Gra-Gri, 1935-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)